Mamie Fowler

543 Main Avenue, San Diego, CA 21098 m.fowler@myemail.com (234) 567-8901

Dedicated senior accountancy manager with 11 + years of leadership experience in the life sciences sector, Adept at supervising teams of 15+ to maintain accurate financial records and facilitating internal and external audits.

Extensive mentorship experience and commitment to nurturing new talent through outstanding professional development training provision.

Key Skills

- Excellent life sciences industry knowledge
- Microsoft Excel
- Leadership and training
- International accountancy
- Teamwork
- Multitasking

Professional Experience

Senior Accounting Manager

BioNano Genomics, San Diego, CA I September 2009 - Present

- Supervise and mentor a team of 15 accountants to prepare routine journal entries and review reconciliations
- Assist the HR department with selecting, interviewing, and onboarding new hires and training five recently qualified accountants in 2020
- Develop company accounting policies and procedures and ensure adherence, reducing discrepancies by 65% and increasing productivity by 43% over two years
- Coordinate internal audits and facilitate all requests from external auditors promptly and accurately

Financial Accountant

One Medical, San Diego, CA] July 2003 - September 2009

- Assisted senior accountants with account reconciliation, meeting 99.8% of deadlines over six years
- Analyzed financial data to make suggestions to improve company procedures and processes
- Provided informal mentorship to three new hires in 2009 and managed orientation activities

Education

Bachelor of Science in Business Accounting

University Of San Diego, San Diego, Ca, September 1997 - September 2001

Master of Accountancy

San Diego State University, San Diego, Ca, September 2001 - June 2003

Certifications

· Certified Public Accountant, 2003